PABLO RODRIGO FRANDALOZO DARDE

Software Engineer

📞 +55 (54) 99665-4611 | @ <u>pablodarde@gmail.com</u> | <u>& https://darde.github.io/</u>

SUMMARY

Software engineer and technical lead with 10+ years of experience building and scaling digital products across global markets. Specializing in modern web architectures and mobile development. Proven track record of leading distributed teams, improving system performance, and driving product-focused engineering decisions.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Technical Lead

May 2023 - Present

Remedy Product Studio

Brazil

- Leading a distributed team across Europe, US, and Latin America in a VueJS/Python (FastAPI) project.
- Improved system stability and reduced incident response times through proactive monitoring; enabled faster feature delivery by fostering best practices and mentoring across a geographically distributed team; contributed hands-on to key architectural decisions that enhanced scalability and maintainability.

Principal Software Engineer

Dec 2021 - May 2023

Pipefy Brazil

Increased developer productivity and code quality by implementing an RFC system
that standardized processes and reduced duplicated code; enhanced team skill
development and retention through launching a successful internal mentoring
program; contributed to faster feature delivery aligned with company goals.

Senior Software Engineer

Dec 2020 - Dec 2021

X-Team Brazil

 Contributed to large-scale SaaS applications using React, NodeJS, NextJS, and microservices architecture.

Senior Software Engineer

Jun 2017 - Dec 2020

RD Station Brazil

- Increased customer engagement and feature adoption through the new drag-and-drop editor, which was responsible for a significant decrease in support tickets;
- Reduced deployment time for frontend projects significantly by introducing the micro-frontend orchestrator; We build the orchestrator and a CLI from scratch, allowing developers to scaffold new frontend apps quickly.

Frontend Specialist

May 2016 - Jun 2017

Daitan Group Brazil

- Led frontend development for projects in partnership with a Palo Alto-based company.
- Enabled smoother and faster deployment cycles through improvements in CI/CD pipelines; strengthened cross-border collaboration, resulting in higher-quality frontend deliverables aligned with partner expectations.



SKILLS

Frontend

React, Redux 9 years
TypeScript 9 years
JavaScript 13 years
Vue 1 year
React Native 4 years

Backend

NodeJS 6 years

Python/Fast API 1 year

Ruby on Rails 2 years

GraphQL 3 years

NextJS 4 years

Complementary Skills

REST * Express * Prisma *
MongoDB * Postgres

Cloud providers/Infrastructure

AWS * GCP * Vercel * GitHub
Actions

Apr 2015 - May 2016

SAP

Brazil

Brazil

• Accessibility enhancement in complex interfaces.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering Mar 2018 - Dec 2021

Cesumar Brazil

Information Systems Technician Mar 2005 - Nov 2007

UFRGS - Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul